Marco Furone Full-stack Developer

London, UK marco.job92@gmail.com M. 07576564916

Profile

Software Developer with 5+ years of experience, excellent **JAVA** development skills, good knowledge of OOP principles and experience with some of its Frameworks.

Gained experience as a **Full-stack** Developer working several times in a similar role using front-end technologies: in particular **JavaScript**, **React** and **CSS**, exposing Web Services and working with Relational and NO-SQL Databases.

Often joined **Agile** projects and used many different technologies and architectures, including micro-services and functional programming languages.

Worked throughout his career in large and small organisations across a wide range of industries including banking, insurance and consulting.

Experience

06/2020 to Current

3D INNOVATIONS London, UK

- Designed and developed an application (and its CMS) from scratch, which shows information and analysis about Market Indexes, taking business requirements and turning them into application functionalities, leading the entire development and delivery of the project using a BDD process.
- Developments and maintenance of a flagship application.
 Moved this application to AWS and improved several heavy SQL queries that resulted in an overall load speed improvement of ~30%.

Technologies:

React (Hooks), JavaScript ES6, Redux, HTML5, CSS (Sass).

Java 8, Spring Boot (Core, Web, Security), Hibernate JPA, Lombok, JUnit, Mockito, Maven.

AWS. SQL.

03/2019 to 01/2020

Credit Suisse London, UK

 Development from scratch of a Data-driven Web Application in a Bank environment, working full-stack with JavaScript (ECMAScript 6), an OOP language (JAVA) and a functional programming language (Clojure).

Part of an **Agile** team interacting with technical and non-technical people (front-office). Used very dynamic technologies to store and retrieve data (GraphQL and MongoDB).

Technologies:

Clojure, Java 8, GraphQL, MongoDB.

React, Redux, JavaScript ES6, HTML5, CSS (Sass).

Docker, Git, Jira, Team City (CI/CD).

01/2018 to 10/2018

ALLIANZ Milan, Italy

- Development, mainly with Java 8 using a TDD approach, of an Application for Document Management that allowed users to upload and view documents.
- Exposed Web Services to external applications and internal back-end components working with a micro-services architecture.
- Development of stand-alone applications for massive upload of documents.

Technologies:

Java 8, Spring, Hibernate, Maven, JUnit, Oracle SQL, CMIS.

JavaScript

Micro-services architecture, REST and SOAP services.

JBOSS, Git, Microsoft TFS (CI/CD).

01/2017 to 12/2017

HIGHWAY Milan, Italy

 Full-Stack Development of a JAVA eCommerce (and its Project Management Application), working in a highly specialised Web Agency.

Technologies: Java, Liferay, SQL, Google Analytics and Paypal APIs.

HTML, CSS, Javascript ES6 (including Aiax, D3.js, JQuery).

Development of a small Client Application using C#.

Technologies: C#, REST services.

Development of a Facebook Chatbot using NodeJS and a NO-SQL database.

Technologies: NodeJS, MongoDB, REST Services, Wit.ai.

NPM (Express, Bootbot, RabbitMQ, node-rest-client, node-schedule).

07/2016 to 12/2016

DELOITTE DIGITAL Milan, Italy

• Front-end and Back-end development of a B2B eCommerce for an important client (MSC Cruise Company), working in an **Agile Scrum** large team.

Technologies:

IBM WebSphere-Commerce: Java, Struts, EJB, JSTL.

Front-End: Javascript (JQuery, Ajax), HTML, CSS, Bootstrap.

Database: SQL, DB2.

05/2016 to 06/2016

GCI Milan, Italy

Front-End and Back-End Development of a Management Web Application.

Technologies: Java, JAX-RS, Hibernate, Maven, MySQL.

HTML, Javascript, AngularJS, Bootstrap.

 Banking consultancy (SSM) for an important Italian Bank (Intesa Sanpaolo) working on a Big Data project.

Technologies: Hadoop (Hive), ETL processes.

www.timesheetevo.com

Developed a web-based SaaS Management Application on my own: *Timesheet Evo*. It is an independent Web Application for managing employee timesheets, expense notes and leave requests.

The website also contains its 'commercial' landing paging, although this is <u>not</u> a real commercial application and was developed entirely by me shortly after my graduation during my free time to explore new solutions and experiment with technologies.

Technologies used: Java, JavaScript, AngularJS 1.x, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, SQL.

Website: http://www.timesheetevo.com

Sample user: timesheetevo@gmail.com; password: 123456

Web Portfolio: http://www.marcofurone.com

GitHub: https://github.com/MarcoJob92

Skills

Programming Languages:

Expert: Java

Proficient: JavaScript

Prior experience: Clojure, NodeJS, C#.

Java:

Spring (Core, MVC, Security), **Hibernate,** JUnit, Maven, Lombok, JAX-RS, JAX-WS, Struts, Servlet, JSP, JSTL, JDBC, EJB, Hadoop (HIVE).

Front-end:

JavaScript (ECMAScript 6), **React** (Hooks, Router), **Redux**, Axios, Ajax, JQuery, npm, **HTML5**, **CSS3**, Sass, Bootstrap.

Good knowledge of:

SQL language, **MongoDB** (NoSQL), **XML** and **JSON** as data exchange formats, **MVC** and **ORM** Patterns, **REST** and **SOAP** Services, **GIT** and **SVN** versioning tools.

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science, March 2016.

University of Messina, Sicily, Italy.

Completion of two OOP courses during the university: **C++** and **Java**.

Thesis title: Design and implementation in java of a Client/Server system for the management of a library.

2-week .NET Framework Course, April 2016.

Milan, Italy.

Technologies: C#, ASP .NET Framework, Entity Framework, SQL Server.